

Belal Abusaleh

(626) 898-0502 | **E**: belalabu@hotmail.com 9100 E Florida Ave, Denver, CO 80247 github.com/belalabu

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Innovative Data Scientist with 3 years of experience in analytics and success in credit risk management, digitization and customer relationship management. Highly accomplished in influencing decision-makers and driving profitability across multiple divisions, including banking credit risk, debt collections, customer relationship management and digitization. Eager to bring expertise to growing organization in challenging new role.

RECENT PROJECTS

Malaria Imaging: Python, Tensorflow/Keras, Pandas, Numpy *github.com/belalabu/projects/tree/master/Malaria*

Building and using a CNN model to correctly identify images of cells with Malaria vs healthy cells. Validation Accuracy of 92%

Supervised learning in Real-Time Bidding: Python, SciKit Learn, Scipy, Pandas

github.com/belalabu/projects/tree/master/RealTimeBidding

Using a variety of supervised learning models to correctly identify if a consumer will click on an ad before advertising company makes a bid for that advertisement.

Unsupervised Learning in Natural Language Processing: Python,

Wordcloud, Sklearn, Pandas

github.com/belalabu/projects/tree/master/Unsupervised%20NLP

Using unsupervised models to correctly cluster horror authors based on their texts

WORK HISTORY

DATA SCIENTIST

11/2018 to CURRENT

Thinkful | Denver, CO

- Designed and implemented various machine learning models for a variety of fields.
- Data cleaning, processing, and selection.
- Statistical Analysis.

INVESTMENT ADVISOR

01/2018 to CURRENT

Foresters Financial | Monrovia, CA

- Provide in-depth analysis to 400 existing households, identifying gaps and weaknesses in current financial plans and establishing solutions by utilizing modeling software and regression.
- Educate and present to clients various investment vehicles available to them to ensure informed decisions be made with their finances.

• Explain workplace benefits to clients such as, retirement options, medical options, and life insurance provided by employer.

FINANCIAL ADVISOR

11/2016 to 01/2018

Ameriprise Financial | Beverly Hills, CA

- Find and qualify new clients via various marketing strategies.
- Determine goals and priorities of a client and write a plan for them to achieve their goals in an appropriate manner.
- Monitor and track the client's progress on a quarterly basis via rebalancing.

SKILLS (

- Python
- Machine Learning
- Predictive Models
- R
- Big Data
- Data Science

- SQL
- Data Visualization
- MATLAB
- MS Excel
- Image processing

EDUCATION ()

BS | Neuroscience

JUN 2015

University of California, Riverside, CA

GPA: 3.5